const quizQuestions11en = 
[{
    question:"GTAW (TIG welding) was originally developed to weld:",
    answers: ["Stainless steel.",
    "Titanium.",
    "Copper.",
    "Magnesium and Aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the use of gases in the MAG welding of common carbon steels, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["with pure CO2 the weld surface becomes bluish.",
    "the weld metal becomes brittle when using a mixture of 82% argon and 18% CO2.",
    "pure CO2 generates less spatter.",
    "pure CO2 generates more spatter."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In oxyfuel gas cutting, the material to be cut is locally:",
    answers: ["heated by flame, melted and removed by the oxygen jet;",
    "heated by the flame, oxidized by the jet of oxygen, and the oxide is melted and expelled by the same oxygen jet;",
    "melted and heated by the jet of acetylene or LPG;",
    "heated by flame, oxidized by acetylene or LPG, melted and expelled by the jet of oxygen."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The oxyfuel gas cutting of carbon steels occurs:",
    answers: ["only due to the heat of the flame;",
    "due to the heat of the flame that melts the metal, which is then “blown” out by the jet of oxygen;",
    "due to heating by the flame, followed by oxidation of the metal and subsequent expulsion of the molten metal by the oxygen jet;",
    "by vaporization of the metal, since it is a process with a high concentration of energy."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the gases is not suitable for oxyfuel gas cutting?",
    answers: ["Compressed air.",
    "Oxygen.",
    "Acetylene.",
    "LPG."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What material can be cut by the OFC process without additional accessory?",
    answers: ["Aluminium.",
    "Copper.",
    "Carbon steel.",
    "Gray cast iron."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A carbonizing (reducing) flame is characterized by:",
    answers: ["an excess of oxygen over acetylene;",
    "an excess of acetylene over oxygen;",
    "the mixture of gases in equal proportion;",
    "higher temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An oxidizing flame is characterized by:",
    answers: ["an excess of oxygen over acetylene;",
    "an excess of acetylene over oxygen;",
    "the mixture of gases in equal proportion;",
    "lower temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which polarity should the electrode holder be connected in the carbon arc gouging process?",
    answers: ["DCEN polarity.",
    "The polarity doesn't matter, because the alternating current should be used.",
    "Whatever polarity, because the metal removal is done by compressed air jet.",
    "DCEP polarity."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A tube of what material would you not use to join two hoses carrying acetylene?",
    answers: ["Aluminium, as it has low mechanical strength.",
    "Carbon steel, as it can oxidized.",
    "Copper, as it reacts with acetylene causing an explosion.",
    "Stainless steel, as chromium reacts with acetylene."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"\"What is the \"\"HF Impulse\"\" function in AC TIG welding of aluminium used for?\"",
    answers: ["To facilitate the arc striking at the beginning of the positive half-cycle.",
    "To facilitate the arc striking at the beginning of the negative half-cycle.",
    "For cleaning the oxide layer.",
    "To strike the arc."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding electric arc is composed of the anodic zone, cathodic zone and arc column. So, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The arc voltage is predominant in the column voltage, as voltage drops in the anodic and cathodic zones are very low due to the fact that their lengths do not exceed 0.001 mm.",
    "The current passing through the cathodic zone is always higher than the current passing through the anodic zone.",
    "If the arc length is increased, it is only the arc column length that is increased, the anodic and cathodic zones remaining the same in size.",
    "If the arc length is increased, all three zones proportionally increase their length and their voltage drop."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding electric arc is composed of the anodic zone, cathodic zone and arc column. So, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The arc voltage is predominant in the column voltage, as voltage drops in the anodic and cathodic zones are very low due to the fact that their lengths do not exceed 0.001 mm.",
    "The current passing through the cathodic zone is always higher than the current passing through the anodic zone.",
    "If the arc length is increased, it is only the voltage drop in the arc column that is increased, the anodic and cathodic voltage drops remaining the same (if the current is kept constant).",
    "If the arc length is increased, all three zones proportionally increase their length and their voltage drop."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding electric arc is composed of the anodic zone, cathodic zone and arc column. So, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The arc voltage is predominant in the column voltage, as voltage drops in the anodic and cathodic zones are very low due to the fact that their lengths do not exceed 0.001 mm.",
    "The current passing through all three zones is the same.",
    "If the arc length is increased, all three zones increase their length proportionally, but between voltage drops it is only the column voltage that increases.",
    "If the arc length is increased, all three zones proportionally increase their length and their voltage drop."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding electric arc is composed of the anodic zone, cathodic zone and arc column. So, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The arc voltage is predominantly composed of voltage drops in the anodic and cathodic zones, even that their lengths do not exceed 0.001 mm.",
    "The current passing through the cathodic zone is always higher than the current passing through the anodic zone.",
    "If the arc length is increased, all three zones increase their length proportionally, but between voltage drops it is only the column voltage that increases.",
    "If the arc length is increased, all three zones proportionally increase their length and their voltage drop."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the electric arc:",
    answers: ["Plasma is an ionized “gas”, composed of electrons and ions, where basically ions are responsible for conducting current.",
    "The process of maintaining the arc (starting from the point that the gas is already ionized) is based on the production of heat due to the collisions of the accelerated electrons with the atoms.",
    "If there were no heat losses from the arc column to the environment, plate and electrode, the arc voltage would be zero.",
    "The electric arc is a perfect converter of electrical energy into thermal energy (no other form of energy is transferred from the arc to the workpiece)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the electric arc:",
    answers: ["Plasma is an ionized “gas”, composed of electrons and ions, where basically ions are responsible for conducting current.",
    "If there were no heat losses from the arc column to the environment, plate and electrode, the arc voltage would be zero.",
    "The ways of obtaining initial plasma in arc welding processes are the high heating achieved by the short circuit or the use of high frequency ignition.",
    "The electric arc is a perfect converter of electrical energy into thermal energy (no other form of energy is transferred from the arc to the workpiece)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the electric arc:",
    answers: ["Plasma is an ionized “gas”, composed of electrons and ions, where basically ions are responsible for conducting current.",
    "Plasma is an ionized “gas”, where the density of ions and free electrons is high, but the current is conducted mainly by the electrons.",
    "If there were no heat losses from the arc column to the environment, plate and electrode, the arc voltage would be zero.",
    "The electric arc is a perfect converter of electrical energy into thermal energy (no other form of energy is transferred from the arc to the workpiece)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A constant voltage type power source is usually used for MIG/MAG because:",
    answers: ["the pulsed transfer is achieved with precise definition of current and pulse time;",
    "it promotes the arc length self-adjustment;",
    "no wire feed speed adjustment is required;",
    "it ensures a high deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A constant voltage type power source is usually used for MIG/MAG because:",
    answers: ["the pulsed transfer is achieved with precise definition of current and pulse time;",
    "no wire feed speed adjustment is required;",
    "it facilitates arc opening;",
    "it ensures a high deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A constant voltage type power source is usually used for MIG/MAG because it:",
    answers: ["promotes the arc length self-adjustment;",
    "allows maintenance of a constant value of arc voltage and welding current regardless of changes in the arc length;",
    "ensures a high deposition rate;",
    "generates less spatter than a constant current power source."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A constant voltage type power source is usually used for MIG/MAG because it:",
    answers: ["allows maintenance of a constant value of arc voltage and welding current regardless of changes in the arc length;",
    "ensures a high deposition rate;",
    "it facilitates arc opening;",
    "generates less spatter than a constant current power source."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding brazing/soldering, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["To ensure better wetting in brazing/soldering, the surface must be cleaned of oxides and heated.",
    "Surface oxides help with wettability between filler metal and base metal as oxygen reduces surface tension.",
    "Brazing of low melting point alloys, such as aluminium and its alloys, is done without filler material.",
    "The capillary effect only works in soldering, whereas in brazing the penetration of metal occurs due to wetting phenomenon."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding brazing/soldering, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Surface oxides help with wettability between filler metal and base metal as oxygen reduces surface tension.",
    "It is possible to braze without capillary effect, as in the case of copper alloys in steel, with flame heating.",
    "Brazing of low melting point alloys, such as aluminium and its alloys, is done without filler material.",
    "The capillary effect only works in soldering, whereas in brazing the penetration of metal occurs due to wetting phenomenon."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following factor is considered important for the choice of gas in MIG/MAG welding:",
    answers: ["The type and thickness of the metal to be welded.",
    "Welder qualification level.",
    "The diameter of the electrode wire to be used.",
    "Welding position."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following factor is considered important for the choice of gas in MIG/MAG welding:",
    answers: ["Welder qualification level.",
    "The metal transfer mode to use.",
    "The diameter of the electrode wire to be used.",
    "Welding position."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following factor is considered important for the choice of gas in MIG/MAG welding:",
    answers: ["Welder qualification level.",
    "The diameter of the electrode wire to be used.",
    "Welding costs.",
    "Welding position."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Covered Electrode welding (SMAW/MMA):",
    answers: ["Due to a longer energized electrode length, a high current density cannot be used (under the risk of overheating), but this factor does make the deposition rate of this process very high.",
    "The deoxidizing elements for the weld are mainly added through the core metal.",
    "The main reason for a low deposition rate of this process, compared to other welding arc processes, are the fact that the current intensity is limited.",
    "The protection of theweld pool and droplets in transfer is achieved exclusively by the slag."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a function of the preheating flame in the oxyfuel cutting.",
    answers: ["To increase the temperature of the steel to its ignition point for cutting.",
    "To provoke the combustion reaction of the carbon contained in the steel and thus releasing additional energy.",
    "To expel from the steel surface any oxide, scale, paint or other foreign substances, which can delay the normal progression of the cutting action.",
    "To reduce the cooling rate of the cut region to avoid the formation of fragile microstructures."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a function of the preheating flame in the oxyfuel cutting.",
    answers: ["To provoke the combustion reaction of the carbon contained in the steel and thus releasing additional energy.",
    "To increase the energy in the form of heat to the workpiece to maintain the cutting reaction (oxidation).",
    "To expel from the steel surface any oxide, scale, paint or other foreign substances, which can delay the normal progression of the cutting action.",
    "To reduce the cooling rate of the cut region to avoid the formation of fragile microstructures."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following recommendations for choosing current type and polarity for TIG welding is correct?",
    answers: ["Welding steels with AC.",
    "Welding aluminium and magnesium with AC.",
    "Welding titanium with DC and electrode in positive polarity (DCEP).",
    "Welding thin plates (2 - 3 mm) of stainless steel with DC and electrode in positive polarity (DCEP)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following recommendations for choosing current type and polarity for TIG welding is correct?",
    answers: ["Welding steels with AC.",
    "Welding titanium with DC and electrode in positive polarity (DCEP).",
    "Welding thin plates (2 - 3 mm) of stainless steel with DC and electrode in positive polarity (DCEP).",
    "Welding nickel with DC and electrode in negative polarity (DCEN)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say about plasma cutting:",
    answers: ["the plasma kerf width is greater than that obtained via oxyfuel gas cutting;",
    "the main gas used is Argon.",
    "it can be used for most metals, except copper and its alloys;",
    "plasma cutting power sources open a non-transferred arc inside of the torch at the beginning of the cutting process."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the effect of increasing the ionization potential of the shielding gas on the arc voltage?",
    answers: ["There is no effect on the arc voltage provided the arc length is kept constant.",
    "It increases the arc voltage.",
    "It decreases the arc voltage.",
    "There is no effect on the arc voltage, what is being changed is the specific arc voltage (measured in V/mm)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is an advantage offered by welding with tubular electrodes (FCAW) compared to welding with covered electrodes (MMA/SMAW)?",
    answers: ["A better possibility of mechanization.",
    "Consumables are of low cost.",
    "Good weld pool control in out-of-position welding.",
    "Fume generation is lower."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is an advantage offered by welding with tubular electrodes (FCAW) compared to welding with covered electrodes (MMA/SMAW)?",
    answers: ["Consumables are of low cost.",
    "High deposition rate.",
    "Good weld pool control in out-of-position welding.",
    "Fume generation is lower."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"TIG welding has the most stable arc because:",
    answers: ["it is easy to control the arc length when using a non-consumable electrode;",
    "the direct current is always used (no arc stability problems associated with alternating current).",
    "the phenomenon of arc length self-adjustment is used.",
    "the flow rate of shielding gas is higher than in other welding processes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"TIG welding has the most stable arc because:",
    answers: ["the direct current is always used (no arc stability problems associated with alternating current).",
    "there is no metal transfer through the arc;",
    "the phenomenon of arc length self-adjustment is used.",
    "the flow rate of shielding gas is higher than in other welding processes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"How to reduce spatter generation when using GMAW welding with pure CO2?",
    answers: ["To use a power source with a constant current type characteristic.",
    "To carry out welding with short-circuiting transfer.",
    "To set an adequate inductance level (at the power source) to control the rate of rising of the short circuit current.",
    "To apply a spray type transfer."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The heat released in the arc column comes from:",
    answers: ["the radiation;",
    "the electrode molten metal passing through the arc;",
    "the ionization of gases present in the arc;",
    "the plasma jet friction effect."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is true of welding parameters in submerged arc surfacing (assuming other parameters are kept unchanged).",
    answers: ["The positive electrode polarity offers less dilution.",
    "The larger the contact tip-to-work distance, the shallower the penetration.",
    "A lower arc voltage reduces penetration.",
    "The use of a thicker electrode results in higher penetration (with the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"at is true of welding parameters in submerged arc surfacing (assuming other parameters are kept unchanged).",
    answers: ["The positive electrode polarity offers less dilution.",
    "The shorter the contact tip-to-work distance, the shallower the penetration.",
    "A higher arc voltage reduces penetration.",
    "The use of a thicker electrode results in higher penetration (with the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"at is true of welding parameters in submerged arc surfacing (assuming other parameters are kept unchanged).",
    answers: ["The positive electrode polarity offers less dilution.",
    "The shorter the contact tip-to-work distance, the shallower the penetration.",
    "A lower arc voltage reduces penetration.",
    "The use of a thicker electrode results in lower penetration (with the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is true regarding the soldering?",
    answers: ["The wettability of filler metal can be measured by the density ratio of the filler metal and the base metal.",
    "Surface oxides help with wettability between filler metal and base metal as oxygen reduces surface tension.",
    "The melting point of filler metal for soldering is less than 450 °C.",
    "The flux application is not required for soldering."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is true regarding the soldering?",
    answers: ["The wettability of filler metal can be measured by the density ratio of the filler metal and the base metal.",
    "The wettability of filler metal can be measured by the contact angle between the filler metal in the liquid state and the base metal.",
    "The melting point of filler metal for soldering is less than 500 °C.",
    "The flux application is not required for soldering."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which process cannot be used for additive manufacturing?",
    answers: ["Covered electrode welding (MMA/SMAW).",
    " TIG (GTAW) welding.",
    "MIG/MAG (GMAW) welding.",
    " Laser directed energy deposition (L-DED)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What kind of defect can possibly occur due to a high content of hydrogen in the coating of covered electrodes when welding low-alloy steels?",
    answers: ["Hot cracking in the weld metal.",
    "Porosity in the weld metal.",
    "Hydrogen induced cracking.",
    "Development of martensite in the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The presence of hydrogen in the argon + hydrogen gas mixtures used for TIG/GTAW will:",
    answers: ["reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding aluminium;",
    "reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding carbon steels;",
    "provide a reducing atmosphere to improve weld surface cleaning;",
    "reduce porosity in carbon steel welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The presence of hydrogen in the argon + hydrogen gas mixtures used for TIG/GTAW will:",
    answers: ["reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding aluminium;",
    "reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding carbon steels;",
    "drastically increase the penetration;",
    "prevent the oxide formation in the molten weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Slowing the cooling rate of a hard-faced material will:",
    answers: ["increase the degree of wear resistance;",
    "decrease the degree of wear resistance;",
    "increase the material hardness;",
    "cause fissuring."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of Plasma Transferred Arc Surfacing?",
    answers: ["Minimum distortion.",
    "Added powder material of a low cost.",
    "Very thick deposition layer.",
    "High heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In submerged arc welding, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["the higher the welding speed, the lower the possibility of porosity and crack formation;",
    "one of the functions of submerged arc welding flux is to provide iron powder to increase the deposition rate;",
    "the submerged arc welding is very suitable for making root passes without backing, but only in the flat position.",
    "the larger the distance between the contact tip and the workpiece (stick-out), the higher the deposition rate (for the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following statement is true regarding the welding processes application methods, and regarding respective established terminologies:",
    answers: ["Semi-automatic welding is that where the torch is moved by a motorized system and the filler metal is fed by the welder.",
    "Robotic and mechanized systems are distinguished by the number of degrees of freedom for movement.",
    "Adaptive control for arc length maintenance is that where the welder adapts the tip-to-work distance for each electrode diameter.",
    "A robot performs semi-automatic welding, as the trajectory is traced by manual programming of a robot operator."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding MIG/MAG welding equipment and consumables, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The static characteristics of electronic power sources for MIG/MAG can be of Constant Current type (for controlled transfer, such as pulsed mode) and of Constant Voltage type.",
    "Push-pull torches are used for thicker electrode wires to help the feeder to propel them.",
    "Most MIG/MAG welding power sources comes from the manufacturer with only one inductance value.",
    "The torch nozzle serves to direct the shielding gas to the weld pool and its diameter depends on the type of base metal to be welded."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct alternative in relation to the adjustment of MIG/MAG process parameters, keeping the other parameters unchanged:",
    answers: ["If you increase the wire feed speed, the arc voltage will take on a slightly lower value.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the arc length also increases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the current also increases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, penetration also increases."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct alternative in relation to the adjustment of MIG/MAG process parameters, keeping the other parameters unchanged:",
    answers: ["As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the arc length also increases.",
    "As the arc voltage is increased, the current takes on a slightly higher value.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the current also increases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, penetration also increases."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct alternative in relation to the adjustment of MIG/MAG process parameters, keeping the other parameters unchanged:",
    answers: ["As the voltage is increased, the current takes on a slightly lower value.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the arc length also increases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the current decreases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, penetration also increases."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding friction welding (FRW), the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["it is necessary for both parts to rotate opposite each other, which is the reason for the high cost of the equipment;",
    "the parts to be joined come into contact with each other only after reaching the temperature of the plastic state, which facilitates joining by crushing/forging;",
    "one of the pieces to be joined must be in motion. This movement may or may not be rotational;",
    "a major limitation of the process is that it cannot be used for welding dissimilar metals."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is desirable for the heat source in welding?",
    answers: ["As large size as possible.",
    "Non-stop functioning.",
    "Maximum thermal efficiency.",
    "Chemical inertness."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is desirable for the heat source in welding?",
    answers: ["As large size as possible.",
    "As small size as possible.",
    "Non-stop functioning.",
    "Chemical inertness."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0"},
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Phase Equilibrium Diagrams.",
    answers: ["Equilibrium diagrams constitute a map of the phases that make up a material as a function of chemical composition and temperature.",
    "Phase diagrams are constructed using analytical math methods.",
    "In phase diagrams, the lever rule allows the chemical composition of each present phase to be calculated.",
    "TTT and CCT diagrams are other forms of phase equilibrium diagrams."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Phase Equilibrium Diagrams.",
    answers: ["Equilibrium diagrams constitute a map of the phases that make up a material as a function of chemical composition and transformation kinetics.",
    "Phase diagrams can be constructed using analytical or physical methods such as dilatometers or thermal analysis.",
    "In phase diagrams, the lever rule allows the chemical composition of each present phase to be calculated.",
    "TTT and CCT diagrams are other forms of phase equilibrium diagrams."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Phase Equilibrium Diagrams.",
    answers: ["Equilibrium diagrams constitute a map of the phases that make up a material as a function of chemical composition and transformation kinetics.",
    "Phase diagrams are constructed using analytical math methods.",
    "In phase diagrams, the lever rule allows you to calculate the percentage of present phases (relative amounts of phases).",
    "TTT and CCT diagrams are other forms of phase equilibrium diagrams."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Phase Equilibrium Diagrams.",
    answers: ["Equilibrium diagrams constitute a map of the phases that make up a material as a function of chemical composition and transformation kinetics.",
    "Phase diagrams are constructed using analytical math methods.",
    "In phase diagrams, the lever rule allows the chemical composition of each present phase to be calculated.",
    "Phase diagrams tell you nothing about transformation kinetics. This information is obtained through the TTT or CCT diagrams."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the cold or hot working processes.",
    answers: ["Cold working increases hardness and tensile strength and reduces elongation as the grains weld together, making relative movement between them difficult.",
    "A material subjected to mechanical forming performed at temperatures above the material's recrystallization temperature does not harden permanently.",
    "The recovery phenomenon is the restoration of the hot worked metal properties without any change in the microstructure.",
    "The recrystallization is the replacement of the hot worked structure by a new group of deformation-free grains."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the cold or hot working processes.",
    answers: ["Cold working increases hardness and tensile strength and reduces elongation as the grains weld together, making relative movement between them difficult.",
    "A material hardens permanently only by being subjected to plastic deformation carried out above the material's recrystallization temperature.",
    "The recovery phenomenon is the restoration of the cold worked metal properties without any change in the microstructure.",
    "The recrystallization is the replacement of the hot worked structure by a new group of deformation-free grains."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the cold or hot working processes.",
    answers: ["Cold working increases hardness and tensile strength and reduces elongation as the grains weld together, making relative movement between them difficult.",
    "A material hardens permanently only by being subjected to plastic deformation carried out above the material's recrystallization temperature.",
    "The recovery phenomenon is the restoration of the hot worked metal properties without any change in the microstructure.",
    "The recrystallization is the replacement of the cold worked structure by a new group of deformation-free grains."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A steel with about 0.8% C, slowly cooled from austenite, will present, at room temperature, a microstructure consisting essentially of:",
    answers: ["alpha ferrite;",
    "bainite;",
    "perlite;",
    "cementite."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When weight and thickness reduction is needed for a structure, what type of steel should be used?",
    answers: ["High strength low alloy steel.",
    "Ferritic stainless steel.",
    "Austenitic stainless steel.",
    "Martensitic stainless steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is the hardest microstructure?",
    answers: ["Pearlite.",
    "Ferrite.",
    "Austenite.",
    "Cementite."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is the softest microstructure at room temperature? ",
    answers: ["Pearlite.",
    "Ferrite.",
    "Austenite.",
    "Cementite."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The ability of a material to exist in two or more atomic structures without changing composition is:",
    answers: ["allotropy;",
    "politropy;",
    "supertropy;",
    "dualtropy."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Grain refining of steel promotes:",
    answers: ["tensile yield strength increase;",
    "creep resistance increase;",
    "corrosion resistance increase;",
    "hardness and ductility increase."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The interpass temperature when welding austenitic stainless steel:",
    answers: ["should always be controlled for thick materials;",
    "must always be kept above 150 °C;",
    "must always be kept below 150 °C;",
    "should only be controlled for very thin plates."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In MIG/MAG welding (GMAW), a small addition of oxygen to argon will:",
    answers: ["reduce the arc stability;",
    "reduce the penetration;",
    "cause the temperature of the molten metal to decrease;",
    "cause the temperature of the molten metal to increase."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When nickel is added to stainless steel which of the following properties is increased?",
    answers: ["Corrosion resistance.",
    "Magnetic feature.",
    "Thermal fatigue resistance.",
    "Carbon stabilization."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When nickel is added to stainless steel which of the following properties is increased?",
    answers: ["Machinability.",
    "Ductility.",
    "Thermal fatigue resistance.",
    "Carbon stabilization."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When nickel is added to stainless steel which of the following properties is increased?",
    answers: ["Thermal fatigue resistance.",
    "Carbon stabilization.",
    "Weldability.",
    "Machinability."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When nickel is added to stainless steel which of the following properties is increased?",
    answers: ["Electrical resistance.",
    "Carbon stabilization.",
    "Machinability.",
    "Thermal fatigue resistance."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When nickel is added to stainless steel which of the following properties is increased?",
    answers: ["Impact values at lower temperatures.",
    "Carbon stabilization.",
    "Machinability.",
    "Thermal fatigue resistance."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper exhibits as a physical property:",
    answers: ["low mechanical strength (300 N/mm2, compared to approx. 700 N/mm2 for steel);",
    "low thermal conductivity;",
    "low tenacity;",
    "low machinability."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding copper, you have to be aware of:",
    answers: ["the fact that copper has a high affinity for nitrogen;",
    "a low resistance to corrosion in relation to the many corrosive fluids;",
    "a low fluidity of the liquid phase (molten phase);",
    "a high thermal conductivity that can cause lack of fusion (or difficulty in fusing)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding copper, you have to be aware of:",
    answers: ["the fact that copper has a high affinity for nitrogen;",
    "a low resistance to corrosion in relation to the many corrosive fluids;",
    "a low fluidity of the liquid phase (molten phase);",
    "the creation of oxides."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding copper, you have to be aware of:",
    answers: ["the fact that copper has a high affinity for nitrogen;",
    "a low resistance to corrosion in relation to the many corrosive fluids;",
    "a low fluidity of the liquid phase (molten phase);",
    "a high thermal expansion that can cause the generation of residual stresses and cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Carbon in iron is present as:",
    answers: ["interstitial alloy element in low carbon steels and as a substitutional element in medium and high carbon steels;",
    "an interstitial alloying element;",
    "a substitutional alloying element;",
    "a solid solution with full solubility."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Carbon in iron is present as:",
    answers: ["interstitial alloy element in low carbon steels and as a substitutional element in medium and high carbon steels;",
    "a limited solubility solid solution;",
    "a substitutional alloying element;",
    "a solid solution with full solubility."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is the most recommended welding process for nickel and nickel alloys:",
    answers: ["OFW;",
    "MMA (SMAW);",
    "TIG (GTAW);",
    "SAW."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is the most recommended welding process for nickel and nickel alloys:",
    answers: ["OFW;",
    "MMA (SMAW);",
    "MIG/MAG (GMAW);",
    "SAW."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is NOT recommended welding process for nickel and nickel alloys:",
    answers: ["MIG/MAG (GMAW);",
    "MMA (SMAW);",
    "OFW;",
    "SAW."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following characteristics DOESN'T depend on the crystalline structure of steel?",
    answers: ["Elasticity.",
    "Thermal conductivity.",
    "Heat expansion.",
    "Elongation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"An 18Cr 10Ni austenitic stainless steel is not sensitive to intergranular corrosion after welding, if its carbon content is:",
    answers: ["more than 0.03 %;",
    "less than 0.03 %;",
    "less than 0.3 %;",
    "less than 0.3%, but if the steel also has 1% titanium."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Intergranular corrosion occurs adjacent to welds in austenitic stainless steels. What actions should be taken, to avoid such corrosion problems?",
    answers: ["Use an overalloyed consumable.",
    "Choose a stainless steel with a carbon content less than 0.03%.",
    "Perform a heat treatment at 600 °C for 1 h immediately after welding is finished.",
    "Perform a heat treatment at 200 °C for 1 h immediately after welding is finished."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"For martensitic transformation, it is true that:",
    answers: ["martensite occurs only in the iron-iron carbide alloy system;",
    "martensitic transformation is based on diffusion phenomena;",
    "the martensitic transformation is a replacement of an interstitial solid solution of carbon in iron by a substitutional solid solution of carbon with increased hardness.",
    "the amount of martensite produced does not depend on the time spent by the material at a specific temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"For martensitic transformation, it is true that:",
    answers: ["martensite occurs only in the iron-iron carbide alloy system;",
    "martensitic transformation is based on diffusion phenomena;",
    "the martensitic transformation is a replacement of an interstitial solid solution of carbon in iron by a substitutional solid solution of carbon with increased hardness.",
    "martensitic transformation depends on the cooling rate from the austenitic range."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In what area of HAZ is there a possibility to find martensite?",
    answers: ["In the region of HAZ which have been heated just over A1.",
    "In a narrow line between HAZ and the base material.",
    "In the normalised area close to A3.",
    "In the grain growth region close up to the Fusion Line."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What might have caused the presence of small cracks in the weld root of the steel with Ceq=0.5%?",
    answers: ["High preheating temperature that led to the formation of martensite in the HAZ.",
    "Preheating time too long that allowed the formation of martensite in the HAZ.",
    "Low preheating temperature that allowed martensite to form in the HAZ.",
    "Welding speed too low which caused the formation of martensite in the HAZ."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is duplex stainless steel?",
    answers: ["A stainless steel with a ferritic-martensitic structure (50% ferrite and 50% martensite).",
    "A stainless steel with a ferritic-austenitic structure (50% ferrite and 50% austenite).",
    "A stainless steel with an austenitic-martensitic structure (50% austenite and 50% martensite).",
    "A stainless steel with a structure of 50% primary austenite and 50% secondary austenite."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following alloy groups would hastelloy belong to?",
    answers: ["Nickel + copper.",
    "Nickel + iron.",
    "Nickel + chromium",
    "Nickel + molybdenum."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which statement regarding aluminium is correct?",
    answers: ["The Young's modulus of aluminium is about three times lower than that of steel.",
    "The Young's modulus of aluminium is about 10 times lower than that of cast iron (very hard material).",
    "Young's modulus of aluminium is lower than that of steel, but higher than that of copper.",
    "The Young's modulus values of aluminium, carbon steel and copper are very close, around 200 GPa."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Austenite is:",
    answers: ["a mixture of perlite and cementite;",
    "the iron carbide Fe3C;",
    "a solid solution of carbon in delta iron;",
    "a solid solution of carbon in gamma iron."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What can we find in a phase diagram?",
    answers: [" The amount of each phase present at equilibrium.",
    "The chemical reactions that may occur.",
    "The changes for a chemical reaction occurring under defined conditions.",
    "The changes for a chemical reaction occurring under different temperatures."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following statements is correct when it treats the existence of Sulphur (S) in an unalloyed steel?",
    answers: ["It increases the risk of cold cracks.",
    "It increases the size of grains in the HAZ.",
    "It increases the risk of hot cracking.",
    "It increases the size of grains in the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following statements is correct when it treats the existence of Sulphur (S) in an unalloyed steel?",
    answers: ["It increases the risk of cold cracks.",
    "It increases the size of grains in the HAZ.",
    "It increases the risk of lamellar tearing.",
    "It increases the size of grains in the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following statements is correct when it treats the existence of Sulphur (S) in an unalloyed steel?",
    answers: ["It increases the risk of cold cracks.",
    "It increases the size of grains in the HAZ.",
    "It causes a low weldability.",
    "It increases the size of grains in the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The effect of molybdenum in a creep resistance steel is:",
    answers: ["to improve the cracking resistance;",
    "to improve the creep resistance;",
    "to improve the impact resistance;",
    "to improve the corrosion resistance at high temperatures."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Generally speaking, aluminium alloys have a wide range of solidification temperatures, and therefore, they have high risk of occurrence of:",
    answers: ["blowholes;",
    "non-metallic inclusions;",
    "cold cracking;",
    "hot cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The hardness of steel can be increased by:",
    answers: ["chromium;",
    "aluminium;",
    "sulphur;",
    "phosphorus."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The hardness of steel can be increased by:",
    answers: ["molybdenum;",
    "aluminium;",
    "sulphur;",
    "phosphorus."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In which temperature interval is chromium-carbide formed (welding stainless steels)?",
    answers: ["100 to 300 °C.",
    "300 to 600 °C.",
    "600 to 900 °C.",
    "900 to 1200 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding stainless steels, in order to avoid the formation of chromium carbides it is important to:",
    answers: ["keep the welding temperature between 600 and 900 °C;",
    "minimise the welding time at the interval 600 to 900 °C;",
    "limit the preheat temperature below 600 °C;",
    "carry out post weld heat treatment at 590 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which temperature range does the intergranular corrosion of stainless steel welds occur at?",
    answers: ["100 to 300 °C.",
    "300 to 600 °C.",
    "600 to 900 °C.",
    "900 to 1200 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which nickel alloys would you choose for aircraft turbojet exhaust ducting?",
    answers: ["Monel alloys.",
    "Inconel alloys.",
    "Incoloy alloys.",
    "Nichrome alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How can you avoid the intergranular corrosion of stainless steel welds?",
    answers: ["Using a steel stabilized with Zr.",
    "Increasing Cr content in the filler material.",
    "Increasing the preheating temperature.",
    "Using a steel stabilized with Ti."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How can you avoid the intergranular corrosion of stainless steel welds?",
    answers: ["Using a steel stabilized with Zr.",
    "Increasing Cr content in the filler material.",
    "Increasing the preheating temperature.",
    "Using a steel with C< 0,03%."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"When weight and thickness reduction is needed for a structure, what type of steel should be used?",
    answers: ["High strength low alloy steel.",
    "Ferritic stainless steel.",
    "Austenitic stainless steel.",
    "Martensitic stainless steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What static strength value of the base material is used in the design of a construction?",
    answers: ["Minimum value obtained by the tensile test of the welded joint.",
    "Value indicated on the material certificate.",
    "Minimum value specified by the standard where this material is included.",
    "Average value specified by the standard where this material is included."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The static safe working stresses used to design a welded carbon steel structure are based on?",
    answers: ["HAZ metal ultimate tensile strength;",
    "HAZ metal yield strength;",
    "Base metal ultimate tensile strength;",
    "Base metal yield strength."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of high strength steels in welded joints can be advantageous:",
    answers: ["when the joint is subjected to low average stresses;",
    "in cases of low cycle fatigue;",
    "in cases of high cycle fatigue;",
    "if it is necessary to avoid problems of weldability."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of high strength steels in welded joints can be advantageous:",
    answers: ["when the joint is subjected to low average stresses;",
    "when the joint is subjected to high average stresses;",
    "in cases of high cycle fatigue;",
    "if it is necessary to avoid problems of weldability."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the creep phenomenon, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["Creep testing procedure is generally quite time consuming;",
    "Temperature does not influence the creep phenomenon;",
    "Creep occurs above the yield limit of the material;",
    "Creep is the elastic deformation that occurs in a material under constant static load, as a function of time and temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is it important to know the “ductile – brittle” transition temperature of the weld joint base metal?",
    answers: ["To predict the creep strength of this metal at low temperatures.",
    "To determine the preheat temperature.",
    "In order to maintain the interpass temperature above this temperature.",
    "To see if the metal would be suitable for working in certain temperature ranges."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is it important to know the “ductile – brittle” transition temperature of the weld joint base metal?",
    answers: ["To predict the creep strength of this metal at low temperatures.",
    "To determine the preheat temperature.",
    "In order to maintain the interpass temperature above this temperature.",
    "To find out the minimum allowable service temperature for the welded joint in question."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About structural elements, it can be said:",
    answers: ["The beams belong to the bars, while the columns belong to the pillars;",
    "Within the structural elements, sheet and plate are synonymous;",
    "Designing a beam consists of selecting a section that resists the shear and bending produced by the applied loads;",
    "Cables (eg steel cables) can withstand torsional and compressive stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About structural elements, it can be said:",
    answers: ["The beams belong to the bars, while the columns belong to the pillars;",
    "Within the structural elements, sheet and plate are synonymous;",
    "Columns: are bars that undergo axial loading;",
    "Cables (eg steel cables) can withstand torsional and compressive stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About structural elements, it can be said:",
    answers: ["The beams belong to the bars, while the columns belong to the pillars;",
    "Within the structural elements, sheet and plate are synonymous;",
    "Beams are bars that are loaded transversely to their longitudinal axis;",
    "Cables (eg steel cables) can withstand torsional and compressive stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding metallic structures, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["Manufacturable requirement is most important compared to other requirements;",
    "The most used welding processes in the fabrication of metallic structures are MIG/MAG, SMAW (MMA) and oxyacetylene welding;",
    "During the fabrication of a metallic structure, design changes are not allowed;",
    "All possible design errors are discovered during the detailing stage (before fabrication of the structure)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which statement regarding intermittent welds is correct?",
    answers: ["Intermittent welds are better for dynamic loads because there is less restriction effect.",
    "Intermittent welds should be avoided for medium to high dynamic loads.",
    "Intermittent welds are recommended where there are high dynamic loads as a crack will be stopped at the end of an intermittent weld.",
    "For equivalent strengths, continuous fillet welds use more filler metal than intermittent fillet welds."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When can a butt weld with permanent backing be considered not adequate for its intended use in a steel structure?",
    answers: ["When the structure does not need an additional mechanical strength.",
    "When the structure is statically loaded and the service temperature is high.",
    "When the structure is statically loaded and the service temperature is low.",
    "When the structure is dynamically loaded and is working at low service temperatures."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The equilibrium of a rigid body exists if:",
    answers: ["the sum of the acting stresses is equal to zero in the three Cartesian directions;",
    "In space problems there are six equilibrium equations (sums of forces Fx, Fy and Fz each equal to zero and sums of moments Mx, My and Mz each equal to zero).",
    "In plane problems there are four equilibrium equations (sums of forces Fx and Fy each equal to zero and sums of moments Mx and My each equal to zero).",
    "In linear problems there are two equilibrium equations: sum of forces Fx = 0 and sum of moments Mx = 0."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the types of links (supports, connections), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The roller support type is represented by, for example, a single pin support;",
    "The hinged type support is represented by, for example, a sliding contact (frictionless smooth surface);",
    "The fixed type support is represented by, for example, a sliding contact (rough surface);",
    "A welded joint is considered as a fixed support and therefore must have a minimum dimension guaranteed by a standard."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the types of links (supports, connections), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The roller support type is represented by, for example, a single pin support;",
    "The hinged type support is represented by, for example, a sliding contact (frictionless smooth surface);",
    "The fixed type support is represented by, for example, a sliding contact (rough surface);",
    "The number of unknowns associated with the support reactions can be from one to six in equilibrium problems of a three-dimensional structure."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the effects of residual welding stresses, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Since the residual stresses along the weld in the base metal are compressive, they may reduce the buckling strength of welded structures.",
    "Generally, they are larger in thin materials.",
    "Generally, harmful effects of residual stresses in thicker materials are less pronounced.",
    "They are higher in materials that have a low yield strength (ferritic steels, austenitic stainless steels...)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the effects of residual welding stresses, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The presence of residual stresses, even at a low level, promotes brittle fracture, hydrogen embrittlement and stress corrosion cracking.",
    "Generally, they are larger in thin materials.",
    "Generally, harmful effects of residual stresses in thicker materials are less pronounced.",
    "They are higher in materials that have a low yield strength (ferritic steels, austenitic stainless steels...)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the effects of residual welding stresses, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["If they reach the yield point of the material, they can cause failures of the welded structures.",
    "Generally, they are larger in thin materials.",
    "Generally, harmful effects of residual stresses in thicker materials are less pronounced.",
    "They are higher in materials that have a low yield strength (ferritic steels, austenitic stainless steels...)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the effects of residual welding stresses, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["They can be responsible for creep flow, dimensional instability, brittle and ductile fracture, fatigue fracture, among others.",
    "Generally, they are larger in thin materials.",
    "Generally, harmful effects of residual stresses in thicker materials are less pronounced.",
    "They are higher in materials that have a low yield strength (ferritic steels, austenitic stainless steels...)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the effects of residual welding stresses, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["They can cause failure in service, especially when added to the stresses applied in service, thus exceeding the strength limit of the material.",
    "Generally, they are larger in thin materials.",
    "Generally, harmful effects of residual stresses in thicker materials are less pronounced.",
    "They are higher in materials that have a low yield strength (ferritic steels, austenitic stainless steels...)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Excessive reinforcement on a weld could result in:",
    answers: ["angular distortion.",
    "longitudinal distortion.",
    "transverse distortion.",
    "plastic distortion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which one of the following statements is true of oxygen?",
    answers: ["Will burn when present in high enough concentrations.",
    "Will support combustion at concentrations as low as 7.5%.",
    "Oxygen is not a factor to consider when fighting fires.",
    "Must be present for a fire to continue."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"How does ISO 9000 define quality?",
    answers: ["\"“Quality is the degree to which a set of inherent characteristics fulfils requirements.\"\"\"",
    "\"\"\"Quality product has no defects and has a long service life\"\".\"",
    "\"\"\"A quality product is one that meets the manufacturer's requirements.\"\"\"",
    "\"\"\"Quality is absolute perfection that can never be achieved but has to be the goal of any manufacturing process.\"\"\""],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What causes burns on the surface of the eye?",
    answers: ["Gamma rays.",
    "Ultraviolet rays.",
    "Light rays.",
    "Microwaves."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The fumes from which of the following metals is more harmful to human health?",
    answers: ["Iron.",
    "Copper.",
    "Lead.",
    "Cadmium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In terms of ISO 9000, one of the sentences below is considered to be the definition of “special process”:",
    answers: ["\"\"\"A process that encompasses two or more very different processes, that is, that cannot be governed by just one standard\"\";\"",
    "\"\"\"A manufacturing process where the conformity of the resulting product cannot be technically verified\"\";\"",
    "\"\"\"A process where the conformity of the resulting output cannot be readily or economically validated\"\";\"",
    "\"\"\"A new manufacturing process for which standards have not yet been developed, so it must be controlled according to the experience of the appointed personnel\"\".\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the elaboration and the necessity to use standards, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["A welding standard, when correctly applied, minimizes the contractor's civil liability for the service;",
    "Only welding engineers can develop welding standards;",
    "The application of a standard does not increase the initial cost of a work, on the contrary, it reduces production costs;",
    "The application of a standard does not increase the initial cost of a work, as qualified personnel and procedures, as well as calibrated equipment, among others, are not mandatory."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About the technique to minimize distortions by pre-fixing parts to be welded, it is possible to say:",
    answers: ["It is most recommended for welding cast iron which is characterized by high coefficients of thermal expansion;",
    "It only guarantees less distortion if the welded joint is subjected to stress relief (still with the fasteners);",
    "After the fixture is removed, the welded joint always distorts;",
    "If on one hand it reduces distortion, on the other hand it can increase residual stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About the technique to minimize distortions by pre-fixing parts to be welded, it is possible to say:",
    answers: ["It is most recommended for welding cast iron which is characterized by high coefficients of thermal expansion;",
    "It only guarantees less distortion if the welded joint is subjected to stress relief (still with the fasteners);",
    "After the fixture is removed, the welded joint always distorts;",
    "If there is plastic deformation without changing the joint geometry, this technique ensures lower levels of distortion and residual stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the properties below increases residual stresses in a welded joint, when its value alone is increased during the selection of material?",
    answers: ["Rupture Strength.",
    "Yield Strength",
    "Thermal Conductivity.",
    "Elongation at Rupture."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the properties below increases residual stresses in a welded joint, when its value alone is increased during the selection of material?",
    answers: ["Rupture Strength.",
    "Thermal Expansion Coefficient.",
    "Thermal Conductivity.",
    "Elongation at Rupture."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the applicability of the Magnetic Particle Testing (MPT), it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The MPT is used to locate only superficial and sub-surface discontinuities, as the attenuation of the magnetic field does not allow detecting discontinuities located deeper from the surface;",
    "In this method, the material tested can be either ferromagnetic, paramagnetic or diamagnetic, since what is essential is that the applied particles must be ferromagnetic;",
    "Stainless steels of all classes, as they are not ferromagnetic, cannot be tested by the MPT method;",
    "It can be applied in the flat position only (since there is no way of keeping the particles in the overhead position)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to the pressure and leak tests:",
    answers: ["The leak testing of a pressure vessel by the bubble test is easy to use and does not imply safety specifications;",
    "The most recommended method to evaluate the mechanical strength of a vessel is the overpressure using the air;",
    "The leak test is widely used in inspection of pressurized or depressurized components, where there is a risk of leakage or penetration of products;",
    "\"If there is a risk of the pressure vessel blasts during the leak test, a solution may be \"\"Pressure Decay leak testing\"\".\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to the pressure and leak tests:",
    answers: ["The leak testing of a pressure vessel by the bubble test is easy to use and does not imply safety specifications;",
    "The most recommended method to evaluate the mechanical strength of a vessel is the overpressure using the air;",
    "Some specific pressure and leak tests, such as overpressure or vacuum, must be performed after careful analysis of the mechanical resistance of the element to be tested, controlling the associated risks;",
    "\"If there is a risk of the pressure vessel blasts during the leak test, a solution may be \"\"Pressure Decay leak testing\"\".\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The quality control of welded joints includes, among other activities and subjects:",
    answers: ["Traceability, equipment calibration and arbitrary welding;",
    "Traceability, Technical documentation and Arbitrary welding;",
    "Equipment Calibration, Technical documentation and Arbitrary welding;",
    "Traceability, Technical documentation and Equipment calibration."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 3834 standard - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\" prescribes ...\"",
    answers: ["a single level of quality requirements;",
    "two levels of quality requirements;",
    "three levels of quality requirements;",
    "four levels of quality requirements;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 5817 standard \"\"Fusion-welded joints in steel, nickel, titanium and their alloys - Quality levels for imperfections\"\" prescribes ...\"",
    answers: ["two levels of quality for imperfections: A and B;",
    "three levels of quality for imperfections: A, B and C;",
    "three levels of quality for imperfections: 1, 2 and 3;",
    "three levels of quality for imperfections: B, C and D."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 15607, a work instruction is:",
    answers: ["a simplified specification of the welding procedure;",
    "a simplified analogue of WPS, used in small companies which cannot afford (for cost reasons) a qualified WPS;",
    "a document that contains main tips on how to perform a welding operation with quality, as well as following safety norms;",
    "one of the WPS sub-items. A WPS can originate 5 to 15 work instructions."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 15607, a work instruction is:",
    answers: ["a document suitable for direct application in the workshop;",
    "a simplified analogue of WPS, used in small companies which cannot afford (for cost reasons) a qualified WPS;",
    "a document that contains main tips on how to perform a welding operation with quality, as well as following safety norms;",
    "one of the WPS sub-items. A WPS can originate 5 to 15 work instructions."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the actions of the arrangements for welding cost reduction:",
    answers: ["\"to reduce, or at least \"\"freeze\"\" the wage of the workforce;\"",
    "application of welding methods with a higher metal deposition rate;",
    "to require welders to use the short arc (reducing the arc voltage will lead to a reduction in electrical energy consumption);",
    "to use alternating current instead of direct current, as the price of a welding transformer is much lower than that of a welding rectifier."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the actions of the arrangements for welding cost reduction:",
    answers: ["\"to reduce, or at least \"\"freeze\"\" the wage of the workforce;\"",
    "to seek of decreasing the “labour/output” ratio of the welding processes;",
    "to require welders to use the short arc (reducing the arc voltage will lead to a reduction in electrical energy consumption);",
    "to use alternating current instead of direct current, as the price of a welding transformer is much lower than that of a welding rectifier."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the actions of the arrangements for welding cost reduction:",
    answers: ["\"to reduce, or at least \"\"freeze\"\" the wage of the workforce;\"",
    "to reduce the consumption of auxiliary materials;",
    "to require welders to use the short arc (reducing the arc voltage will lead to a reduction in electrical energy consumption);",
    "to use alternating current instead of direct current, as the price of a welding transformer is much lower than that of a welding rectifier."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the actions of the arrangements for welding cost reduction:",
    answers: ["\"to reduce, or at least \"\"freeze\"\" the wage of the workforce;\"",
    "to increase the duty cycle of welding equipment;",
    "to require welders to use the short arc (reducing the arc voltage will lead to a reduction in electrical energy consumption);",
    "to use alternating current instead of direct current, as the price of a welding transformer is much lower than that of a welding rectifier."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the actions of the arrangements for welding cost reduction:",
    answers: ["\"to reduce, or at least \"\"freeze\"\" the wage of the workforce;\"",
    "to seek of reduction of failures resulting from poor training of the workforce;",
    "to require welders to use the short arc (reducing the arc voltage will lead to a reduction in electrical energy consumption);",
    "to use alternating current instead of direct current, as the price of a welding transformer is much lower than that of a welding rectifier."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the actions of the arrangements for welding cost reduction:",
    answers: ["\"to reduce, or at least \"\"freeze\"\" the wage of the workforce;\"",
    "to avoid the use of equipment with operating problems, inadequate PPE, ... which can harm the health of employees with costs of absences, occupational diseases, ...",
    "to require welders to use a short arc (a lower arc voltage will lead to a reduction in electrical energy consumption);",
    "to use alternating current instead of direct current, as the price of a welding transformer is much lower than that of a welding rectifier."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"By increasing the cooling rates, welds on reinforcing steels will have:",
    answers: ["higher mechanical strength;",
    "lower thermal stresses;",
    "a higher level of impurities (they will have no time to emerge on the weld surface);",
    "higher porosity (pores will not be able to emerge on the weld surface)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"By increasing the cooling rates, welds on reinforcing steels will have:",
    answers: ["increased hardness values;",
    "lower thermal stresses;",
    "a higher level of impurities (they will have no time to emerge on the weld surface);",
    "higher porosity (pores will not be able to emerge on the weld surface)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"By increasing the cooling rates, welds on reinforcing steels will have:",
    answers: ["decreased ductility values;",
    "lower thermal stresses;",
    "a higher level of impurities (they will have no time to emerge on the weld surface);",
    "higher porosity (pores will not be able to emerge on the weld surface)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It can be said that automated welding, allows, in relation to manual welding:",
    answers: ["to increase the deposition rate of the welding process;",
    "to perform welding out of position;",
    "to reduce the volume of non-destructive tests of the welded joint;",
    "to obtain uniform and predictable quality (repeatability)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It can be said that automated welding, allows, in relation to manual welding:",
    answers: ["to increase the deposition rate of the welding process;",
    "to perform welding out of position;",
    "to reduce the volume of non-destructive tests of the welded joint;",
    "increase productivity (increase the process operation factor)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It can be said that automated welding, allows, in relation to manual welding:",
    answers: ["to increase the deposition rate of the welding process;",
    "to perform welding out of position;",
    "to reduce the volume of non-destructive tests of the welded joint;",
    "to reduce the rework rate, that is, reduce the waste of material and time."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It can be said that automated welding, allows, in relation to manual welding:",
    answers: ["to increase the deposition rate of the welding process;",
    "to perform welding out of position;",
    "to reduce the volume of non-destructive tests of the welded joint;",
    "to increase operational security."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It can be said that automated welding, allows, in relation to manual welding:",
    answers: ["to increase the deposition rate of the welding process;",
    "to perform welding out of position;",
    "to reduce the volume of non-destructive tests of the welded joint;",
    "to increase, in some cases, the welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The following is considered a method of stress relieving heat treatment of low-alloy carbon steels:",
    answers: ["Heat the workpiece quickly so that it does not reduce the hardness of the material;",
    "Heat the workpiece slowly so as not to harden the material;",
    "Heat, maintain and cool down the entire workpiece inside an oven;",
    "Heat the workpiece immediately after welding to 200 - 300 °C, without letting the weld cool down;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The following is considered a method of stress relieving heat treatment of low-alloy carbon steels:",
    answers: ["Heat the workpiece quickly so that it does not reduce the hardness of the material;",
    "Heat the workpiece slowly so as not to harden the material;",
    "Heating, coating the workpiece with insulation, maintenance followed by hot air-controlled cooling;",
    "Slow heating after welding, to a temperature above the steel transformation temperature, for a period of time, followed by slow cooling;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The following is considered a method of stress relieving heat treatment of low-alloy carbon steels:",
    answers: ["Heat the workpiece quickly so that it does not reduce the hardness of the material;",
    "Heat the workpiece slowly so as not to harden the material;",
    "Separate heating of each part of the workpiece inside an oven (when the dimension does not allow to treat the whole workpiece), provided that the part that remains outside is covered by insulation;",
    "Heat the workpiece immediately after welding to 200 - 300 °C, without letting the weld cool down;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"}]
    ;